Guide to the Minnie Bruce Pratt Papers, 1870s-2005, bulk 1975-2005 RL.01046
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Family Series, 1870s-2005 and undated, 15 boxes
  - Brown-Carr Family, 1870s-2005 and undated, 6 boxes
    - Martin, Ruth Brown, 1928, 1957, 1979, 1993 (Box 75)
    - Miscellaneous family papers, 1897, 1901, 1938, and undated (Box 75)
    - Brown Country Store ledger, Episcopal Cemetery, 1964, 1986-1992 (Box 75)
    - Pushmataha Methodist Church guest books, 1971-1978 and undated (2 folders) (Box 75)
    - Pushmataha Methodist Church records (photocopies), ca.1870-1883 (Box 75)
    - Tilghman, Christopher Carr, Gilder/Brown family history (Box 76)
    - Photographs, ca.1870s-2000s (folders 1-7 of 13) (Box 76)
    - Photographs, ca.1870s-2000s (folders 8-13 of 13) (Box 77)
    - Pushmataha, Alabama photograph album, 1900s-1910s (Scrapbook 1)
    - Martin, Ruth Brown photograph album, 1979 (Scrapbook 2)
    - Pushmataha, Alabama photograph album, 1970s-1980s (Scrapbook 3)
  - Pratt Family, 1880s-2004 and undated, 6 boxes
    Primarily composed of materials related to or retained by Pratt's mother, Virginia Brown Pratt, the subseries includes legal and financial papers, correspondence, mementos, genealogical materials, and photographs. Materials are organized alphabetically by subject and offer information about Virginia Pratt's childhood, marriage to W. Luther Pratt, work, and relatives. The subseries includes letters exchanged by Pratt's parents from 1939 to 1940 during their courtship, letters from Marvin Weaver to Pratt's mother regarding his 1975 divorce from Pratt, and the 1981 letter in which Pratt came out to her mother as a lesbian.
    - Virginia Pratt
      - Bibb County Department of Pensions and Security, employment, 1955-1974 (Box 78)
      - Bibb County High School, 1914-1916, 1937, 1941, 1948 (Box 78)
      - The Bibonia, 1937-1938 (2 folders) (Box 78)
      - Bridal guest book, 1936 (Box 78)
      - Correspondence, 1933-1967 (6 folders) (Box 78)
    - Virginia Pratt
      - Correspondence, 1968-1998 (8 folders) (Box 79)
    - Virginia Pratt
      - Correspondence, 1999-2004 (4 folders) (Box 80)
      - Correspondence and other materials, undated (Box 80)
    - Virginia Pratt
      - Education, 1919-1924, 1933-1942, 1958, 1978, 1986 (Box 81)
      - Family documents (Box 81)
      - Financial papers/ledger book, 1952-1968 (Box 81)
      - Golden 50s, University of Alabama reunion book, 1992 (Box 81)
      - Photographs, 1920s-1940s, 1980s-2000s (3 folders) (Box 81)
    - Pratt Family
      - Business and property papers, 1945, 1948-1955, 1972 (Box 81)
    - Pratt Family
      - Family history papers, 1898, 1966-1973 (Box 82)
      - Geneaology, 1993, 1998 (Box 82)
      - Marsh, Lethean papers, 1986-2004 and undated (4 folders) (Box 82)
      - Overton, Maude Brown papers, 1911-1917, 1929 (Box 82)
      - Photographs, ca.1880s-1940s (Box 82)
      - Pratt, Judge W. L., 1895, 1900, 1951, and undated (Box 82)
      - Clippings, 1921, 1947, 1958, and undated (Box 83)
      - Land grants, deeds, quit claims, 1890s-1910s and undated (Box 83)
      - Photographs (3 folders) (Box 83)
    - Virginia Pratt
      - School scrapbook and photograph album, 1920s; 1927-1928 (2 scrapbooks) (Scrapbook 4)
    - Photographs (Oversize-box 1)
  - Minnie Bruce, 1946-1966 and undated, 11 boxes
    The Minnie Bruce Pratt subseries contains materials from Pratt's childhood up to her marriage to Marvin Weaver in 1966, including correspondence, journals, early poems, mementos, and scrapbooks. Pratt had several international pen pals as a child; other correspondence is from family members and from Minnie Bruce to her parents as a college student. The subseries contains Pratt's earliest poems, written at Camp Cotaquilla in 1960, and the handwritten letter draft she composed to German pen pal Horst Werner defending segregation. Arrangement is chronological.
    - Childhood photographs (Box 84)
    - Correspondence, 1951-1959 (Box 84)
    - Elementary school, 1953-1956 and undated (3 folders) (Box 84)
    - School photographs (Box 84)
    - Church, 1956-1964 (Box 84)
    - Junior high school, 1960-1961 and undated (Box 84)
    - Camp Cotaquilla, 1960 (Box 85)
    - Correspondence, 1960 (Box 85)
    - High school, 1961-1964 (Box 85)
    - Slides, Homecoming, deep sea fishing, Montana, The Great Snow, Easter, home scenes, 1961-1962 (Box 85)
    - Correspondence, 1961 (Box 85)
    - Auburn University pre-college English course, 1962-1963 (Box 85)
    - Correspondence, 1962-1964 (Box 85)
    - Slides, Beauty Walk, Schultz Creek, USA High School Band Tour, high school graduation, 1963-1964 (Box 85)
    - Correspondence, 1963 (4 folders) (Box 85)
    - Correspondence and other materials, undated [pre-1964] (Box 85)
    - College, 1964-1968 (folder 1 of 3) (Box 85)
    - College, 1964-1968 (folders 2-3 of 3) (Box 86)
    - Correspondence, 1964 (3 folders) (Box 86)
    - Journal, 1964 (Box 86)
    - Journal inserts, 1964 (folder 1 of 2) (Box 86)
    - Journal inserts, 1964 (folder 2 of 2) (Box 87)
    - Poetry, 1965 and undated (Box 87)
    - Correspondence, 1965 (5 folders) (Box 87)
      Includes a run of letters from former suitor John Potts.
    - Blue Ridge, 1966 (Box 87)
    - Correspondence, 1966 (folder 1 of 4) (Box 87)
    - Correspondence, 1966 (folders 2-4 of 4) (Box 88)
    - Marriage, 1966 (Box 88)
    - Photographs from marriage and other events (Box 88)
    - Correspondence, undated (folders 1-4 of 5) (Box 88)
    - Correspondence, undated (folder 5 of 5) (Box 89)
    - Baby book, 1946-1949 (Scrapbook 5)
    - Picture album, 1946-1966 (Scrapbook 6)
    - Band scrapbook, 1958-1959 (Scrapbook 7)
    - Chi Omega scrapbook, ca.1964-1966 (Scrapbook 8)
    - Chi Omega scrapbook, ca.1964-1966 (Scrapbook 9)
    - University of Alabama scrapbook, 1965-1966 (Scrapbook 10)
    - 1966 calendar (Oversize-box 1)
  - Ransom Weaver and Ben Weaver, 1968-2004 and undated, 1 boxes
    Items in the Ransom Weaver and Ben Weaver subseries are primarily photographs, as well as programs and magazines from Ransom's rowing events.
    - Ransom Weaver papers, 1968, 1974, 1984-1985, 1990, 2003, and undated (Box 89)
    - Photographs, 1968-1978 and undated (Box 89)
    - Photographs of Ransom, 1990s, 2003 (Box 89)
    - Photographs of Ben, 1990-2004 (Box 89)
    - Rowing magazine featuring Ransom (Oversize-box 1)
  - Leslie Feinberg, 1991-2005, 3 boxes
    This subseries is CLOSED.
    - Leslie Feinberg material (Box 135-137)
- Activism Series, 1973-2002 and undated, 13 boxes
  The Activism Series documents Pratt's work as an activist supporting diversity and fighting intolerance. The series comprises newspaper clippings, fliers, correspondence, and logisitical arrangements pertaining to Pratt's organizing, conference participation, and personal research. The Activism Series contains four subseries that appear in alphabetical order: Anti-Ku Klux Klan, Fayetteville, National Endowment for the Arts (NEA), and Other Issues. The Anti-Ku Klux Klan subseries contains materials related to Pratt's research about the Klan as an anti-racist activist. The Fayetteville subseries comprises materials pertaining to Pratt's early grass roots organizing efforts in Fayetteville, North Carolina. The National Endowment for the Arts subseries documents the public debate that occurred after Senator Jesse Helms referred to Pratt's work as pornography and attempted to revoke her NEA grant. The Other Issues subseries spans Pratt's years as an activist and reflects her interest in a variety of issues. Pratt's original folder titles were retained.
  - Anti-Ku Klux Klan, 1977-1984 and undated, 3 boxes
    During the late 1970s and early 1980s, Pratt researched the Ku Klux Klan due to her desire to fight intolerance. The subseries chiefly comprises newspaper clippings that document Klan activity, but also includes the readings, KKK propaganda, and anti-racist newsletters that Pratt read to learn about the Klan. Materials are organized alphabetically by subject, with files on geographic KKK activity located at the beginning of the subseries.
    - Alabama Klan clippings, 1979-1981 (Box 90)
    - California Klan clippings, 1980-1982 (Box 90)
    - Connecticut Klan clippings, 1980-1982 (Box 90)
    - D.C. and suburbs Klan clippings, 1980-1982 (Box 90)
    - Florida and Georgia Klan clippings, 1980-1984 (Box 90)
    - Mississippi, Louisiana, and Arkansas Klan clippings, 1980-1983 (Box 90)
    - New York, New Jersey, Pennsylvania, and Vermont Klan clippings, 1979-1982 (Box 90)
    - North Carolina Klan clippings, 1980-1983 (Box 90)
    - Tennessee and Kentucky Klan clippings, 1979-1982 (Box 90)
    - Texas Klan clippings, 1980-1982 (Box 90)
    - United States Klan violence, 1980s (Box 90)
    - International Klan clippings, 1980-1981 (Box 90)
    - Anti-Klan contacts and correspondence, 1980-1981 (Box 90)
    - Anti-semitism and KKK, 1980-1982 (Box 90)
    - Armageddon, 1983-1984 (Box 90)
    - Change of heart victory stories, 1980-1981 (Box 90)
    - Chivalry/protection and and the KKK, 1984 (Box 90)
    - Class/KKK, 1980-1982 (Box 90)
    - Clippings and reports, 1980s (folder 1 of 2) (Box 90)
    - Clippings and reports, 1980s (folder 2 of 2) (Box 91)
    - Gays and KKK, 1977-1983 (Box 91)
    - General history, 1979-1982 (Box 91)
    - General tactics, 1980s (2 folders) (Box 91)
    - Greensboro clippings, 1979-1984 (Box 91)
    - Jesse Jackson, anti-Semitism, 1984 (Box 91)
    - Land and the KKK, 1980-1983 (Box 91)
    - Morals, bad women, and the KKK, 1980-1981 (Box 91)
    - Name-calling/KKK, 1980-1981 (Box 91)
    - Paramilitary/KKK violence, 1979-1981 (Box 92)
    - Police and the KKK, 1983 (Box 92)
    - Southern Struggle, 1980 January-1981 May (Box 92)
    - TUFF (Those United to Fight Facism) newsletters, 1980 (Box 92)
    - Women against KKK, general, 1980-1982 (Box 92)
    - Women attacked by the Klan, 1980-1981 (Box 92)
    - Women in the Klan, 1979-1981 (Box 92)
  - Fayetteville, 1977-1993 and undated, 3 boxes
    After completing graduate studies at the University of North Carolina at Chapel Hill, Pratt moved to Fayetteville, North Carolina to accept her first teaching position, at Fayetteville State University. Pratt became active in grass roots organizing, particularly focusing on women's issues. The subseries includes organizational minutes and notes, subject files, clippings, and correspondence related to Pratt's work in the community. Materials are arranged alphabetically by subject.
    - Charlotte-Mecklenburg Council on the Status of Women, 1975-1976 (Box 92)
    - Cumberland County Council on the Status of Women, 1975-1979 (3 folders) (Box 92)
    - Cumberland County Council on the Status of Women Day Care Task Force, 1976 (Box 92)
    - Dave's Radio case, 1977 February (Box 93)
    - Domestic violence, 1976-1978 (2 folders) (Box 93)
    - Education, Title XI, affirmative action, 1972-1977 (Box 93)
    - Fayetteville State University Continuing Education/Women, 1977 (Box 93)
    - Joann Little/correctional facilities, 1975-1976, 1987 (Box 93)
    - Military women, 1976-1977 (Box 93)
    - NOW (National Organization for Women) Battered Women Seminar, 1976-1977 (Box 93)
    - NOW Battered Women, One of These Days...POW! skit, 1977-1982 (Box 93)
    - NOW, Fayetteville/Cumberland County, general, 1977-1980, 1992-1993 (folders 1-2 of 3) (Box 93)
    - NOW, Fayetteville/Cumberland County, general, 1977-1980, 1992-1993 (folder 3 of 3) (Box 94)
    - NOW newsletter, Fayetteville/Cumberland County, 1975-1982 (Box 94)
    - NOW, North Carolina state conferences, 1977 (Box 94)
    - Rape crisis line, 1976-1977 (Box 94)
    - Rape seminar, 1976 June 5 (Box 94)
    - Tae Kwan-Do, 1976-1977 (Box 94)
  - National Endowment for the Arts (NEA), 1985-1992 and undated, 3 boxes
    After Pratt received a NEA grant in 1990, Senator Jesse Helms referred to her work as pornography during a well-publicized speech on the Senate floor. Collectively Pratt and the other targeted poets, Chrystos and Audre Lorde, issued a statement that discussed the importance of diversity and art. The subseries begins with the poets' statement, followed by other materials organized alphabetically by subject. The subseries comprises primarily newspaper clippings, but also includes correspondence, court transcripts, and newsletters from each side of the debate. The subseries documents Helms' attempts to remove NEA funding from targeted artists. Although first created by Pratt in 1990, the subseries contains legal precedents to censorship cases that date back to the mid-1980s.
    - An Open Letter from Three Lesbian Writers on Censorship, 1990 July (Box 94)
    - Clippings, 1990-1992 (folders 1-4 of 10) (Box 94)
    - Clippings, 1990-1992 (folders 5-10 of 10) (Box 95)
    - Correspondence, 1990-1992 (Box 96)
    - Crime, PR and reviews, undated (Box 96)
    - Gay Community News, 1990 September-1990 November (Box 96)
    - Handbook, undated (Box 96)
    - Journal of the American Family Association, 1990 September-1991 January (Box 96)
    - Legal hearings, 1985-1990 (Box 96)
  - Other Issues, 1973-2002 and undated, 7 boxes
    The Other Issues subseries documents the protests, marches, conferences, and festivals Pratt attended in her work as an activist. The subseries also demonstrates the topics she researched to facilitate her activism. Arranged alphabetically by subject, the subseries contains newspaper clippings, fliers, schedules, logistics for events, and correspondence.
    - Abortion/terrorism, 1984-1985 (Box 96)
    - Anti-pornography clippings, 1981-1985 (Box 96)
    - Anti-semitism, 1981-1987 (Box 96)
    - Anti-semitism/women, 1981-1983 (Box 96)
    - Arab women, United States, 1983-1984 (Box 96)
    - Asian-American, 1981-1987 (Box 96)
    - Assimilation, 1983-1987 (Box 96)
    - The Atlanta Lesbian Feminist Alliance, 1982 August 19-22 (Box 96)
    - Christian myth, general, 1983-1985 (Box 96)
    - Cincinnati riots, 2001 (Box 96)
    - Civil Disobedience, 1979-1987 (Box 96)
    - Cross-cultural communication, 1980s (Box 97)
    - Economy and women, 1975-1977 (Box 97)
    - Eighth Michigan Womyn's Music Festival, 1983 August (Box 97)
    - Fliers, miscellaneous activism, 1980s and undated (Box 97)
    - Immigration and Naturalization Service and gays, 1990 (Box 97)
    - International Lesbian and Gay Association, 1991 (Box 97)
    - International Women's Year, 1976-1977 (Box 97)
    - Jewish culture/women, 1982-1991 (Box 97)
    - LAW (Ladies Against Women), 1984 (Box 97)
    - Latinas, 1982-1984 (Box 97)
    - Lesbianism and feminism, 1979-1985 (Box 97)
    - Lesbian rights and sexuality, 1975-1977 (Box 97)
    - LIPS, 1983-1987 (Box 98)
    - LIPS press packet, Memorial Day action, 1984 May 30 (Box 98)
    - Look to the Women for Courage: Stories from the Seneca Encampment slide show, 1983 (2 folders) (Box 98)
    - Madre, 1984-1985 (Box 98)
    - March on Washington for Lesbian and Gay Rights, 1987 October 11 (3 folders) (Box 98)
    - Matthew Shepard clippings, 1998-1999 (Box 98)
    - Matthew Shepard, correspondence regarding attack, 1998 (Box 98)
    - Mautner (Mary-Helen) Benefit, 1993 March (Box 99)
    - Moral Majority, 1983-1987 (Box 99)
    - Motherhood, 1978-1991 (Box 99)
    - Mumia Abu-Jabal, 1995, 1998-2000 (2 folders) (Box 99)
    - National Gay and Lesbian Task Force training, 1995 (Box 99)
    - NOW conference, 1975 (Box 99)
    - National People's Campaign, Caravans for Justice, 1995 September 15-October 2 (Box 99)
    - National People's Campaign March, 1995 May 6 (Box 99)
    - Native American women, 1980-1986 (Box 99)
    - North Carolina Humanities Committee, 1977 (Box 99)
    - Not In Our Name, 1984 (Box 99)
    - Peace for Cuba Rally, 1994 February 12 (Box 99)
    - PVN (The People's Video Network), 1996-1997 (Box 99)
    - Protests, anti-capitalism, Quebec 2001 April (Box 99)
    - Protests, IMF, World Economic Forum, Bush, Washington, D.C., 2001-2002 (Box 99)
    - Protests, Workers World demonstrations, 2001-2005 (Box 100)
    - Protests, World Economic Forum/Globalization, Washington D.C. and New York, 2001-2002 (Box 100)
    - Protests, World Trade Organization, Seattle, 1995 (Box 100)
    - Race and rape, 1980-1984 (Box 100)
    - Race/sex, 1980-1984 (Box 100)
    - Racism, general, 1983-1987 (Box 100)
    - Racism, white women against, 1981-1987 (Box 100)
    - Racism, women against, 1980s (Box 100)
    - Racism in Women's Movement, 1980s (Box 100)
    - Rainbow Flags for Mumia, 1999 (2 folders) (Box 100)
    - Rape, general, 1981-1984 (Box 101)
    - Reagan, Central America, 1983-1986 (Box 101)
    - Resistance, general, 1980s (Box 101)
    - Resistance, lesbians against intolerance, 1980-1984 (Box 101)
    - Sexuality, 1987-1989 (Box 101)
    - South Africa apartheid, 1983-1990 (Box 101)
    - Southeastern Gay Conference, 1977-1978 (Box 101)
    - Sweet Honey in the Rock, 1978 (Box 101)
    - Technology, Science, the Environment, 1980s (Box 101)
    - Wilmington Ten, 1977 April (Box 101)
    - Women of color, 1980s (Box 101)
    - Women and discrimination, 1986-1989 (Box 101)
    - Women's Equality/Suffrage Day, 1976 August 26 (Box 101)
    - Women and higher education, 1984-1990 (Box 101)
    - Women's studies, feminist, 1976-1979 (Box 101)
    - Women's studies, Modern Language Association, 1973-1978 (Box 101)
    - Women's studies, National Women's Studies Association, 1976-1981 (Box 102)
    - Women's studies, National Women's Studies Association workshops, 1975-1984 (Box 102)
    - Women's studies, North Carolina, 1978-1981 (Box 102)
    - Women's studies, Southeastern Women's Studies Association, 1979-1981 (2 folders) (Box 102)
    - Workfare, 2001-2002 (Box 102)
    - Zionism/Palestinian, 1980s (Box 102)
  - Daybooks, 1976-1996; 19 folders (Box 135, Box 138)
    Scope and Contents
    Pratt's daybooks contain daily appointments, travels, political activities, social activities, and general biographical information. The daybooks include significant encounters with Adrienne Rich, J. Gamez, and Chris Whimson. They also include NC ERA organization meetings, Womanwrites, and Feminiary meetings.
- Teaching Series, 1978-2005 and undated, 10 boxes
  Pratt began her career as a professor of women's studies in the late 1970s. The Teaching Series documents Pratt's work as an educator at various universities, primarily The Union Institute and Hamilton College. The chronologically arranged series comprises course syllabi, materials to supplement teaching, seminar evaluations, contracts, general faculty documents, catalogs, newspaper clippings, and correspondence. Pratt kept an extensive series of files related to courses she taught on international women's studies. This series of files is arranged alphabetically by geographic location. The series also contains correspondence from Mumia Abu-Jamal during his application process to The Union Institute for graduate studies. Pratt's original folder titles were retained.
  - Fayetteville State University (Box 103)
    - Southern Women's Equity Project, 1978-1980 (Box 103)
    - Black Women in America (course), 1979 Spring (2 folders) (Box 103)
    - Black women's studies sources, 1979-1982 (3 folders) (Box 103)
  - Lesbian studies sources, 1979-1993 (folder 1 of 4) (Box 103)
  - Lesbian studies sources, 1979-1993 (folders 2-4 of 4) (Box 104)
  - Fayetteville State University, Woman's World radio reports, 1980 (Box 104)
  - Shaw University, 1980-1981 (Box 104)
  - Cazenovia College, 1982 November 1-5 (Box 104)
  - International women's studies sources, 1982-1988
    Associated with Pratt's courses at the University of Maryland and George Washington University.
    - International readings, 1985-1986 (Box 104)
    - Africa, 1985-1988 (Box 104)
    - Africa, South Africa, 1981-1987 (Box 104)
    - Arab/East Mediterranean, 1982-1985 (Box 104)
    - Argentina, 1984-1986 (Box 104)
  - International women's studies sources, 1982-1988 (Box 105)
    - Asia miscellaneous, 1984 (Box 105)
    - Canada, 1985-1988 (Box 105)
    - Caribbean, 1986-1987 (Box 105)
    - Central America, 1985-1987 (Box 105)
    - Chile, 1985-1986 (Box 105)
    - China, 1983-1987 (Box 105)
    - Cuba, 1984 and undated (Box 105)
    - Egypt, 1985 (Box 105)
    - England, 1982-1984 (Box 105)
    - France, 1982-1984 (Box 105)
    - Germany/Austria, 1982, 1987 (Box 105)
    - Guatemala, 1986-1987 (Box 105)
    - India, 1982-1987 (Box 105)
    - Iran, 1987 (Box 105)
    - Israel, 1984-1987 (Box 105)
    - Japan, 1984-1989 (Box 105)
    - Latin America/Spain, 1983-1987 (Box 105)
    - Mexico, 1986 (Box 105)
    - New Zealand/Australia, 1985-1986 (Box 105)
    - Nicaragua, 1984-1986 (Box 105)
    - Pakistan, 1984-1986 (Box 105)
    - Philippines, 1983-1988 (Box 105)
  - Letters of interest, 1984-1985 (Box 106)
  - University of Maryland, Women, Art, and Culture (course), 1984-1985 (Box 106)
  - George Washington University, 1984-1988 (Box 106)
  - George Washington University, Women, Literature, and the Arts (course), 1985 September 5-December 5 (Box 106)
  - Vermont College, Adult Degree Program, 1985 September 13-22 (Box 106)
  - University of Maryland, 1985-1993 (Box 106)
  - George Washington University, Women, Literature, and the Arts (course), 1986, 1988 (2 folders) (Box 106)
  - Correspondence, 1988-1993 (Box 106)
  - Women's studies, general, 1980s (Box 106)
  - The Union Institute
    - Women's Needs seminar, 1989-1991 (Box 106)
    - Contracts, 1990-2004 (Box 106)
  - The Union Institute (Box 107)
    - Entrance colloquium, general, 1992-2000 (Box 107)
    - The Worker and Her Writing seminar, 1993 (Box 107)
  - Hamilton College, job application, 1993-1994 (Box 107)
  - The Union Institute
    - Racism Committee, 1993-1995 (Box 107)
    - Gender seminar, 1994 (Box 107)
    - Entrance colloquium, 1994 December 2-11 (Box 107)
    - Entrance colloquium, 1995 December 8-17 (Box 107)
    - Writing In-Between seminar, 1996 May-June (Box 107)
    - Change-of-status, 1996-1997 (Box 107)
    - Diversity, 1997-2000 (Box 107)
    - Problems, 1997-2001 (Box 107)
  - The Union Institute (Box 108)
    - Projects, 1997-2002 (Box 108)
    - Self-evalutation, 1997-2004 (Box 108)
    - Writing In-Between seminar, 1998 September 23-27 (Box 108)
    - Faculty development, 1998-1999 (Box 108)
    - Faculty research, 1998-2001 (Box 108)
    - President letter, 1999 (Box 108)
    - Faculty development, 1999-2000 (Box 108)
    - Miscellaneous, 1999-2001 (Box 108)
    - Ethics, 1999-2003 (Box 108)
    - Learning, 1990s (Box 108)
    - Entrance colloquium, racism, 2000 October 20-29 (Box 108)
    - Mumia Abu-Jabal application, 2000-2004 (Box 108)
  - The Union Institute (Box 109)
    - Narratives of Power: Place, Race, and Gender in Cincinnati seminar, 2001 August 30-September 3 (6 folders) (Box 109)
      Includes materials used for seminar development dating back to 1999.
    - Writing In-Between seminar, 2002 June 21-25 (Box 109)
  - Hamilton College
    - Contract, 2002-2003 (Box 109)
    - Housing, 2002-2003 (Box 109)
  - Hamilton College (Box 110)
    - Lecture series, 2002-2003 (Box 110)
    - Meetings, 2002-2003 (Box 110)
    - Office, 2002-2003 (Box 110)
    - Hamilton organizing and miscellaneous, 2002-2003 (2 folders) (Box 110)
    - Upstate New York organizing, 2002-2003 (folders 1-3 of 7) (Box 110)
  - Hamilton College (Box 111)
    - Upstate New York organizing, 2002-2003 (folders 4-7 of 7) (Box 111)
  - The Union Institute, correspondence, 2002-2003 (Box 111)
  - Hamilton College
    - Chandra Mohanty book launch, 2003 April 7 (Box 111)
    - Feminist Perspective on Class in the United States (course), 2003 Spring (Box 111)
  - The Union Institute
    - Writing In-Between seminar, 2003 October 22-26 (Box 111)
    - Faculty Appointments and Status Committee, 2004 (Box 111)
    - Lay-offs, 2004 (Box 111)